shpg.org 2017-02-24

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date: June 17, 2013

This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by ShareProgress (“ShareProgress,” “we,” or “us”) when you access the ShareProgress Service (including through the websites of our partners), how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms of Service.

## Information We Collect

**Our Service:** We may collect personally identifiable information about you through our Service when you obtain an account, such as your name and email address. If you choose to purchase a product from us, we or our third-party payment processors will also collect your payment information, such as your credit card number, telephone number and billing address. We also collect data through our partners (customers) who use our Service (including by embedding our code on their websites) to analyze usage of their websites. When you use our Service or if you visit such websites, your browser may send us certain information about you as described below. We do not send any promotional emails; however, we may send you service related emails related to your account.

**Cookies Information:** We may send one or more cookies — a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters — to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser and lets us learn about your behavior and usage patterns when you are on our Service. A cookie may also convey anonymous information about how you browse a partner website to us. We do not use cookies to collect personal information about you. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.

**Log File Information:** Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page on our Service. When you access the Service, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other similar information.

**Clear Gifs Information:** When you access the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our Users anonymously. We do not use these clear gifs to collect any personally identifiable information from your ShareProgress account. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our Service, and make ShareProgress better for our Users and partners.

We do not use the technologies described above to collect personal information about you and use them only to collect data in the aggregate.

## How We Use Your Information

We use the information that we collect to operate and maintain our Service, and to help our partners improve their online offerings.

We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) monitor the effectiveness of our Service and the offerings of our partners; (b) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns; (c) diagnose or fix technology problems; (d) and allow our business partners to deliver advertisements to you as described below.

## How We Share Your Information

**Personally Identifiable Information:** ShareProgress will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of ShareProgress (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). Any personally identifiable information you elect to make publically available on the Service will be available to other Users. If you remove information that you have made public on the Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Service, or if other Users have copied or saved that information.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain ShareProgress services and those of our partners. Non-personally identifiable information may be stored indefinitely.

**Instances where we are required to share your information:** ShareProgress will disclose your information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement; (b) to enforce our Terms of Service or to protect the security or integrity of our Service; and/or (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of ShareProgress, our Users or others.

**What happens in the event of a change of control:** We may buy or sell/divest/transfer the company (including any shares in the company), or any combination of its products, services, assets and/or businesses. Your information such as customer names and email addresses, and other User information related to the Service may be among the items sold or otherwise transferred in these types of transactions. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcies, dissolutions, reorganizations, liquidations, similar transactions or proceedings involving all or a portion of the company.

**Ads:** We may use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. In connection with this advertising, we, along with third-party business partners, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) to allow our third-party business partners, including Google, ad servers, and ad networks, to serve you advertisements (“ads”) based on your prior visits to our Service. These ads are delivered to you on third-party websites and services across the Internet. These third-party business partners use technology to send, directly to your browser or mobile device, the ads and ad links that appear on third-party sites, and will automatically receive your IP address when they do so. Along with cookies, they may also use other technologies (such as JavaScript, device identifiers, location data, and clear gifs, see above) to compile information about your browser’s or device’s visits and usage patterns on the Service, and to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to optimize and personalize the advertising content. ShareProgress does not sell, rent, or share the information we collect directly from you or about you from third parties with these third-party business partners for such parties’ own marketing purposes. You may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or you may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page. Google has additional information available about their Remarketing Privacy Guidelines, Policies, and Restrictions.

The ShareProgress Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party ad servers and ad networks. Please contact or consult the respective privacy policies of such ad servers or ad networks for more information.

## Storage and Processing

Your information collected through the Service may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which ShareProgress or its subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities. ShareProgress may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction, and you consent to the transfer of information to the U.S. or any other country in which ShareProgress or its parent, subsidiaries, affiliates or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

## How We Protect Your Information

ShareProgress is concerned with protecting your privacy and data, but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to ShareProgress or guarantee that your information on the Service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our industry standard physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

## Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, ShareProgress will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

## Your Choices About Your Information

You can contact us directly at [support@shareprogress.org](mailto:support@shareprogress.org) to review and correct the information about you that ShareProgress keeps on file.

## Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important to us. For that reason, ShareProgress does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to access or use the Service or to provide any personal information to ShareProgress. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@shareprogress.org](mailto:support@shareprogress.org).

## Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by ShareProgress in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Service, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have a link or advertisement on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies.

## California Privacy Rights

Users who are California residents may request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, certain information about the personally identifiable information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personally identifiable information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to [support@shareprogress.org](mailto:support@shareprogress.org).

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures materially, we will post those changes on the Service to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. When we change the policy in a material manner we will let you know and by updating the ‘effective date’ at the top of this page.
